ALCHEMY OF SOULS PART 2
&lrm;還魂 &lrm;第二部
Uk and Bu-yeon have promised to go their separate ways.
&lrm;阿煜和復妍已約定好要分開
I heard there was no physical intimacy between them,
&lrm;聽說他們倆之間並沒有肌膚之親
so it will be easier to part ways.
&lrm;那應該能斷得乾淨俐落
It is a relief that they were not in a deep relationship.
&lrm;現在反倒該慶幸 &lrm;他們的感情並非十分深厚
But I remember
&lrm;不過他們
the two of them drinking together at night.
&lrm;曾在夜裡一起喝過酒耶
for nothing ever happened between them.
&lrm;是相當清白、純潔的關係
Just now,
&lrm;方才
I felt the energy within you.
&lrm;你體內的氣息襲向了我
The ice stone?
&lrm;冰石？
Yes.
&lrm;對
What a powerful energy.
&lrm;這股力量真的十分強大
Do you really think I will be able to control this and take it out?
&lrm;我當真能操控並取出它嗎？
I have always wanted to stop,
&lrm;我一直希望能停下來
but right now, I do not.
&lrm;現在卻不想那麼做
Do not ever think that again.
&lrm;你別再興起那種念頭
Although, even if you do,
&lrm;即便你那樣想
I will never grant it to you.
&lrm;我也絕不會如你所願
I am sorry.
&lrm;對不起
And…
&lrm;還有…
thank you.
&lrm;謝謝妳
Since we have stopped, let us think about how to deal with this situation.
&lrm;既然停下來了 &lrm;就來思考該如何收拾這個局面吧
Why are you turning the light on?
&lrm;你為何點燈？
Turn it back off.
&lrm;快熄掉
If we want to be together, we must retract the promise.
&lrm;我們想繼續在一起的話 &lrm;就得撤銷約定
The promise was made, after all.
&lrm;都已經約定好了
Lord Park was there as well when I made that promise,
&lrm;許下約定時
which also makes it a promise between Songrim and Jinyowon.
&lrm;所以也算是松林與辰曜院間的約定
That promise saved Seo Yul's life, so it was worth it.
&lrm;多虧有那個約定才救活了徐律 &lrm;所以沒關係
I will ask the leader for his understanding
&lrm;我會去取得首領的諒解
and have your mother agree to retract the promise we made.
&lrm;也得與妳母親達成協議 &lrm;才能撤銷那個約定
Have her agree to it?
&lrm;達成協議？
Do you plan to threaten my mother?
&lrm;你要去脅迫我娘？
I will convince her just like anybody would.
&lrm;當然得去說服她，如同其他人所為
"I promise to be a good man."
&lrm;“我往後會寵愛她
"Please allow me to marry your daughter."
&lrm;請允准令嬡與在下的婚事”
Sounds convincing.
&lrm;挺不錯的呢
Try convincing me too.
&lrm;也試著來說服我吧
No, we need to take care of the situation first.
&lrm;不可以，我們得先收拾這個局面
If we get distracted again,
&lrm;要是再偏離重點
it will not be easy to keep our heads.
&lrm;就難以找回理智了
All right.
&lrm;好吧
Let us save it for later and focus on taking care of things.
&lrm;那就之後再繼續，現在先收拾局面
You have met my mother without me a few times, right?
&lrm;即便我不在場 &lrm;你也見過我娘好幾次吧？
How was she then?
&lrm;她的態度如何？
What have you done?
&lrm;你在做什麼？
Perhaps you happen to enjoy things like that?
&lrm;難道妳有那方面的偏好嗎？
Being locked up in a dark room and getting poked by needles?
&lrm;喜歡把人囚禁在漆黑的房裡 &lrm;用針扎人之類的？
-I should not have mentioned the needles. -Needles? What do you mean?
&lrm;早知道就別提針的事
No, it is nothing.
&lrm;沒什麼，別在意
I shall comply with her even if she pokes me with needles.
&lrm;縱使她用針扎我，我也會跪地服從
Leaving you to deal with this may not be the best idea.
&lrm;看來由你處理似乎不太妥當
I should go home as promised.
&lrm;我先遵照約定回家吧
You are going to leave?
&lrm;妳就這樣回去嗎？
If I do not go, it will be troublesome for Lord Park,
&lrm;我賴著不走，會讓首領為難
and my mother will only hate you more.
&lrm;也會讓我娘對你更加反感
First, I shall go home and put her at ease.
&lrm;我先回去讓她安下心來
Then I will try talking to her.
&lrm;之後再找機會跟她談
All right, you do that.
&lrm;好，那就這樣吧
I will also discuss it with Lord Park and come up with a solution.
&lrm;我也會與首領商議找出解決方法
Naksu's soul will disappear from her body soon.
&lrm;她體內的落壽很快就會消失
Once the soul of Jin Bu-yeon, the true owner of that body, awakens,
&lrm;一旦那副身軀的真正主人 &lrm;陳復妍的靈魂甦醒
Naksu's soul will disappear.
&lrm;落壽的靈魂就會隨之消失
Where is Young Master Seo?
&lrm;徐律少爺在哪裡？
He woke up and is well.
&lrm;他順利醒過來了
He left to meet Lord Park.
&lrm;因急著找朴進首領，他已先離開
Goodbye.
&lrm;那失陪了
I guess he went to tell him directly
&lrm;他應該是親自去傳達
what he had written in the letter.
&lrm;他在信中提及的內容
Does that mean everyone will find out that the woman with Young Master Jang
&lrm;這表示張煜少爺 &lrm;身邊的女人是落壽的事
is Naksu?
&lrm;會眾所皆知嗎？
Jang Uk, I want you to sleep at home from now on.
&lrm;張煜，你接下來要乖乖回家
-Do not sleep here. -All right.
&lrm;-別再待在這了 &lrm;-好
And tell Maidservant Kim that I will be back soon.
&lrm;也要轉告金道主說我很快就會回家
I will.
&lrm;知道了
I bought honey biscuits and left them in my room.
&lrm;我買了一些你喜歡的藥菓放在我房裡
Go and eat them.
&lrm;你拿去吃
-Honey biscuits? -Yes.
&lrm;-藥菓？ &lrm;-嗯
I heard they were your favorite, so I bought some every time I went out.
&lrm;聽說你喜歡吃 &lrm;我每次出門都會買回來
-How much did you buy? -A lot.
&lrm;-妳買了多少？ &lrm;-非常多
You might fall down. Walk facing forward.
&lrm;妳這樣會跌倒的，面向前方走
We will be apart for a while. I want to look at you every chance I get.
&lrm;今晚起就見不到你了 &lrm;所以我要先多看幾眼啊
There is not a single place where I cannot go,
&lrm;雖然這世上沒有我去不了的地方
but I do not want your mother to hate me even more,
&lrm;但我不能再做出惹妳母親不快的事了
so you should hold on.
&lrm;所以妳得多擔待點
You should secretly visit.
&lrm;那就悄悄潛入
Climb over the wall like Seo Yul did last time.
&lrm;跟徐律上回一樣翻牆進來
Look at you, excitedly asking me to break in.
&lrm;竟然一臉開心地要人闖入妳家
By the way,
&lrm;話說回來
how did you find the entrance to where I was locked up?
&lrm;你一開始是怎麼進到我待的房間？
That door is hard to find.
&lrm;那道門很難找的
Door?
&lrm;門？
What is this?
&lrm;這是什麼？
It just opened
&lrm;門是開著的
as if someone had left it open.
&lrm;彷如有人微微打開一般
It just opened?
&lrm;門是開著的？
It is likely that I broke it while fighting the soul shifter.
&lrm;可能是我打鬥時弄壞的
That might be why the barrier broke.
&lrm;所以結界才會被解開
I see.
&lrm;這樣啊
Then what did you think of me when we first met?
&lrm;那你第一眼見到我時有什麼想法？
I found you unusual
&lrm;我覺得妳很奇特
and suspicious for being locked up in a room like that.
&lrm;加上被監禁著，所以也有點可疑
I liked you from the start.
&lrm;我一開始就喜歡上你了
I knew the moment I saw you.
&lrm;我第一眼就認出來了
You are my husband.
&lrm;我的夫婿
You are my master.
&lrm;我的師父
You once felt the same way.
&lrm;原來你也曾這樣
The blue marks
&lrm;兩道藍色的光
bloomed in her eyes like flowers.
&lrm;像花一樣綻放在她眼裡
I do not care
&lrm;你沒有
that you did not recognize me when we first met.
&lrm;在第一眼就認定我也無所謂
This time…
&lrm;這次…
I recognized you first.
&lrm;是我先的喔
Let us go.
&lrm;走吧
You should still be resting. What was it that could not wait?
&lrm;你應該多加休息
There is something I feel responsible for.
&lrm;有件事我必須負起責任
Is it something that I also need to hear?
&lrm;連我也需要一起聽嗎？
What is it?
&lrm;是什麼事？
It is about Uk and Jin Bu-yeon.
&lrm;是關於阿煜與陳復妍的事
Goodness, Yul is unbelievable.
&lrm;唉唷，阿律那傢伙真是的
Grandfather.
&lrm;爺爺
Did Young Master Seo tell you something?
&lrm;你從徐律少爺那裡聽說了什麼嗎？
He talked about Jin Bu-yeon.
&lrm;是有關陳復妍的事
He said he wishes to take full responsibility.
&lrm;他說一切都由他來負責
The promise with Lady Jin was made to save my life,
&lrm;既然與陳院長的約定是為了要救我
so I will visit her and make sure it is retracted.
&lrm;那我會親自向她表明要對此負責 &lrm;讓她撤銷約定
Was that all he said?
&lrm;他只說了那些嗎？
Did he say anything else about Jin Bu-yeon?
&lrm;他沒提到其他有關陳復妍的事嗎？
Yun-ok.
&lrm;贇鈺
I have told you time and again
&lrm;我都囑咐過多少次了
Do not even be curious about him.
&lrm;甚至連關切都不要
He did not tell them about Naksu?
&lrm;他沒說落壽的事？
Even after he had planned to get rid of her at Danhyanggok?
&lrm;他明明打算陪她到斷響谷 &lrm;再除掉她的
Cho-yeon left by herself?
&lrm;超妍自己回去了？
Yes, Young Master Seo asked her to leave without you.
&lrm;是的，徐律少爺請她回去的
Seo Yul?
&lrm;徐律嗎？
How do you think
&lrm;究竟阿律
Yul is going to convince Lady Jin?
&lrm;要用什麼辦法說服陳院長呢？
I do not know.
&lrm;我也不曉得
He just said that my mother would wait if I told her
&lrm;他只是要我轉告我娘
that Seo Yul will visit her soon to talk about what he knows.
&lrm;請她靜候他的來訪
He is not one to speak rashly,
&lrm;他從不會空口說白話
so his plan is one that will work.
&lrm;絕對有什麼可行的盤算
Shall I ask him to convince your mother about us too?
&lrm;我們的事也託他 &lrm;一併說個好話，如何？
Our situation is not the same.
&lrm;不能與他們混為一談
She utterly detests Jang Uk,
&lrm;她雖然對張煜恨之入骨
but she does not dislike you.
&lrm;卻一點都不討厭你
But…
&lrm;不過
why does she disapprove of Uk so much?
&lrm;為何她誓死不肯接受阿煜啊？
Because it agonizes her to see the person she hates…
&lrm;看到恨之入骨的人幸福的樣子
be so happy.
&lrm;會讓她痛苦不已
Yul is going to meet Lady Jin
&lrm;阿律要去拜訪陳院長
and try to convince her to retract the promise.
&lrm;說服她撤銷約定
Yul is truly amazing.
&lrm;不愧是阿律
He is helping his friend as soon as he wakes up.
&lrm;一醒來就先忙著張羅朋友的事
So I told him, "Uk has already made up his mind."
&lrm;所以我告訴他，你心意已決
"Do not get involved and just focus on recovering."
&lrm;叫他不要拖著虛弱的身體出面協調
And I stopped him.
&lrm;便阻止了他
Why would you stop him from helping out a friend?
&lrm;你為何要阻止？他是在幫朋友的忙耶
You told me that you were going to give up.
&lrm;你不是親口告訴我要放棄嗎？
-My lord. -That is what he said.
&lrm;-首領 &lrm;-是他自己說的
If Young Master Seo helps,
&lrm;若阿律少爺願意幫忙
are you willing to try and convince Lady Jin?
&lrm;那你有下定決心要說服陳院長了嗎？
I took her daughter from her without even asking for permission,
&lrm;我擅自帶走她女兒
so I understand her anger.
&lrm;她會發火也無可厚非
I will do what I can to get rid of her hatred.
&lrm;我打算先消除她對我的厭惡
I heard the news.
&lrm;我聽說了
Thank you for helping.
&lrm;謝謝你願意幫忙
I am merely taking responsibility.
&lrm;我只是為自己引發的事負責罷了
You genuinely helped us.
&lrm;多虧你，我們才有一線曙光
You may have noticed from what I said last time,
&lrm;你之前聽我說過應該略知一二
but there was no room for me in his heart.
&lrm;我先前完全找不到空隙攻陷他的心
But now I get to stay by his side.
&lrm;不過現在我能待在他身邊了
Is it not great?
&lrm;不覺得很好嗎？
I am not sure.
&lrm;這很難說
You will cause each other pain.
&lrm;你們會讓彼此陷入痛苦的
Why would you say that?
&lrm;你為何要那麼說？
We are all friends, are we not?
&lrm;我們都是朋友啊
Friends?
&lrm;朋友…
If you knew what I had planned to do at Danhyanggok…
&lrm;妳要是知道我抱著 &lrm;何種決心前往斷響谷
you would not smile and call me a friend.
&lrm;妳絕對無法笑著稱我為朋友
You look unhappy.
&lrm;你看起來心情不太好
Is it because it still hurts?
&lrm;是因為身體還沒痊癒嗎？
Yes.
&lrm;對
It hurts.
&lrm;我很難受
Perhaps it is because I woke up from a horrible dream.
&lrm;感覺像是從一場煎熬的夢中醒來
Did you have a bad dream?
&lrm;你做了惡夢嗎？
There is someone I have cherished for a very long time…
&lrm;我夢見我與心儀許久的人
and I dreamt of disappearing with her.
&lrm;一同消失
But when I woke up, it turns out…
&lrm;夢醒後發現只剩我一人
that I will remain and she will disappear.
&lrm;那個人卻獨自消失了
I feel both angry and disheartened.
&lrm;我覺得怒火中燒又空虛
But most importantly, my heart aches for her…
&lrm;重要的是那個人很難受又令人心疼
and it agonizes and saddens me.
&lrm;讓我既痛苦又傷心
I cherish all the memories I had in Danhyanggok.
&lrm;我很喜歡在斷響谷的那些回憶
Have we…
&lrm;我們…
ever met before at Danhyanggok?
&lrm;之前曾在斷響谷見過嗎？
You wanted to go there to find your true identity.
&lrm;妳說過到了那裡 &lrm;也許就能知道自己是誰對吧？
Go and find out who you really are.
&lrm;去弄清楚妳到底是誰吧
Then you will realize what it was that I had planned to do at Danhyanggok
&lrm;那麼我是抱著何種決心去斷響谷
and why you and Uk will only end up
&lrm;以及妳和阿煜為何會讓彼此陷入痛苦
causing each other pain.
&lrm;這些妳都會知曉
No, I do not wish to.
&lrm;不，我不要
I will not go if that is what is waiting for me.
&lrm;若是那樣，我不想去
If I cannot be with Jang Uk because of the truth…
&lrm;倘若不能待在張煜身邊
I do not wish to find out.
&lrm;我就不想知道
You may not wish to find out…
&lrm;就算妳不想知道…
but you will.
&lrm;最終妳也會知曉
You asked me
&lrm;你曾請求我
to turn a blind eye even though you were dying.
&lrm;即便知道你可能會死 &lrm;也要佯裝不知情
I ask the same of you.
&lrm;現在我要提出同樣的請求
Please turn a blind eye.
&lrm;佯裝不知情吧
Your foolish friend will give you time.
&lrm;妳的傻朋友會等著妳
But if you ever need me…
&lrm;但若是妳需要我
you can come and find me.
&lrm;隨時都可以來找我
Young Lady Bu-yeon.
&lrm;小姐
I heard the news.
&lrm;我聽說了
I am very happy for you.
&lrm;真是太好了
Thank you.
&lrm;是啊
Young Master Jang even asked Lord Park
&lrm;少爺也拜託首領
to help him convince your mother to change her mind.
&lrm;協助他來挽回妳母親的心
He did?
&lrm;是這樣嗎？
I knew things would turn out this way.
&lrm;我早就料到會這樣
I am glad that it was you who ended up with him.
&lrm;我真的很慶幸是妳陪在少爺身邊
Do you really think…
&lrm;我真的
it will be all right for me to stay by his side?
&lrm;可以待在他的身邊嗎？
Of course.
&lrm;那當然
Now all that is left for us to do is to prepare for the wedding.
&lrm;現在我們只要好好籌備婚禮就行了
Young Master Jang is meeting someone from the palace.
&lrm;少爺正在接見宮裡派來的人
We should head home first.
&lrm;我們先回家吧
-All right. -Come on.
&lrm;-好 &lrm;-來
His Majesty the King will be summoning you today.
&lrm;今日王將會召見你
But before that, the Crown Prince wishes to see you.
&lrm;在此之前，世子邸下希望能見你一面
Inside this chest is an item that belongs to His Royal Highness.
&lrm;這裡面裝的是世子邸下的物品
If you happen to have the same item, he wants you to bring it with you.
&lrm;他吩咐說若你擁有同樣的物品 &lrm;請務必帶進宮
He has ordered that you open it when no one is around you.
&lrm;當你要打開確認時，請確保四下無人
This is the Gold Plaque that the King left behind for his son.
&lrm;這是王為了讓子嗣繼承王位 &lrm;所賜的金牌
What is he playing at?
&lrm;他在打什麼算盤？
Is that the King's Star?
&lrm;那是帝王星嗎？
He is a dangerous star who can take your place whenever he wants.
&lrm;是顆隨時會奪走您寶座的危險之星
Your Royal Highness.
&lrm;邸下
Good.
&lrm;好
As for the turtle, I could not find it anywhere.
&lrm;小的四處翻找，都遍尋不著烏龜蹤影
Someone must have discarded it.
&lrm;牠應該是被丟至遠方了
Lord Dang-gu gave orders to hold a funeral,
&lrm;當具首領下令要為她收殮治喪
but this lad insisted that you come to see her first.
&lrm;但這傢伙卻吵著要你親自過來一趟
I am sure she is happy to see you well.
&lrm;現在看到了，她應該很開心
-What is that? -Well…
&lrm;-這是什麼？ &lrm;-那個啊
It was something she cherished dearly.
&lrm;是她十分珍惜的物品
I do not understand why. She never even used that when it rained.
&lrm;她在雨天時從未撐過 &lrm;不曉得為何那麼珍惜
Does she not have a family member who can hold her funeral?
&lrm;她全然沒有家眷能替她治喪嗎？
No.
&lrm;是的
She said the world she knew was filled with filth and darkness.
&lrm;她說她這輩子都在 &lrm;骯髒又黑暗的世界打滾
But she said you made the world seem clean and bright.
&lrm;只有你是澄淨又明亮的存在
Find her a place where it is warm with lots of sunlight.
&lrm;請幫她找個溫暖、日光充足之處
I will also attend the funeral.
&lrm;我也會幫忙處理她的後事
Yes, Young Master.
&lrm;好的
I thought those memories came from this.
&lrm;我本以為那些記憶都是來自這顆藍玉
But was I wrong?
&lrm;難道不對嗎？
What is going on?
&lrm;究竟是怎麼回事？
You will realize why you and Uk will only end up causing each other pain.
&lrm;妳和阿煜為何會讓彼此陷入痛苦
Will I be able to find out if I go to Danhyanggok?
&lrm;去斷響谷能找到答案嗎？
Young Lady Bu-yeon.
&lrm;小姐
Young Master Jang is here.
&lrm;少爺回來了
Jang Uk.
&lrm;張煜
Hey.
&lrm;嗯
I have to go to the palace immediately. It will not take long.
&lrm;我臨時要進宮一趟，馬上就回來
I need to get changed.
&lrm;我還要更衣
Are you going to keep staring?
&lrm;妳要繼續看著嗎？
No, now is not the time to turn the light off.
&lrm;不行，妳現在熄燈會很危險
Did you get that scar from getting stabbed by that sword?
&lrm;那道疤就是被那把劍刺傷的嗎？
Yes.
&lrm;嗯
So that was the moment
&lrm;原來
that you were dying to know
&lrm;你就是想知道
how she felt.
&lrm;她那一刻的心情
Everyone says she did it to avenge her family's death.
&lrm;所有人都說她是在報家門之仇
But I just could not know
&lrm;但我卻無從知曉
if she truly did not
&lrm;她是否真的
go easy on me.
&lrm;連我都不願放過
It is a sad…
&lrm;真是道悲痛
and terrible wound.
&lrm;又駭人的傷
I do not wish to see the memory of that moment.
&lrm;我不想看到那一刻的記憶
Do you
&lrm;妳
still see her memories?
&lrm;還會看到她的記憶嗎？
I just do not wish to see someone else's memories.
&lrm;我是說我不想看到不屬於我的記憶
They are hers, not mine.
&lrm;那是別人的，不是我的
You said seeing that tree in Danhyanggok
&lrm;妳之前說去斷響谷找到樹
might help you remember who you are.
&lrm;也許就能知道妳是誰
-Do you want me to go with you? -No.
&lrm;-要不要我陪妳去？ &lrm;-不用
I think I was confused about that too.
&lrm;那似乎也是我搞錯了
We do not need to go.
&lrm;所以不去也無妨
You should get changed and go.
&lrm;你繼續更衣，待會一路小心
All right. Wait for me here.
&lrm;好，等我回來
Yes, I will be waiting.
&lrm;好，我等你回來
What is going on?
&lrm;怎麼回事？
You were feeling elated earlier,
&lrm;妳剛才的心情分明這麼雀躍
but you seem a little down.
&lrm;怎麼好像突然變得很消沉？
It is just hard to believe that you told me to wait.
&lrm;因為我不敢相信你竟然會要我等你
You either always told me to leave
&lrm;你之前總是趕我走
or just never came back.
&lrm;不然就是乾脆不回來啊
Wait here. Do not go anywhere.
&lrm;妳別亂跑，乖乖等我
All right.
&lrm;好
I will quickly be back by your side.
&lrm;我很快就會回到妳身邊
I promised you…
&lrm;我承諾過
that I will always be by your side.
&lrm;會一直陪在你身邊啊
You were looking for Young Master Seo. Did you see him?
&lrm;妳不是在找阿律少爺？見到他了嗎？
I saw him leave earlier.
&lrm;我剛才看他出去了
No, it is fine.
&lrm;不必了
I will take care of it myself.
&lrm;我自己處理就好
-Here it is. -What is that medicine for?
&lrm;-找到了 &lrm;-那是什麼藥？
It is used to examine corpses
&lrm;這是檢屍時用的藥
to reveal hidden scars.
&lrm;可以顯露出看不見的疤
A soul shifter's blue mark is like a scar, so applying this will reveal it.
&lrm;還魂人身上消失的藍色印記也是疤 &lrm;撒上這種藥便會顯現
What do you plan to do with it?
&lrm;妳打算用它來做什麼？
She said she did not want to find out…
&lrm;她說她不想知道
so I plan to show her.
&lrm;所以我打算讓她看清事實
I saved your life,
&lrm;你可是多虧我才撿回這條命
and you come here to threaten me with her secret?
&lrm;現在居然拿她的祕密來威脅我？
If it sounds like a threat, then so be it.
&lrm;若妳覺得這是威脅，那便是吧
Do not try to keep Naksu locked up in Jinyowon.
&lrm;請妳別再試圖將落壽困在辰曜院
Are you telling me to let her stay with Jang Uk?
&lrm;那麼你難道要我讓她留在張煜身邊？
If that is what she wants,
&lrm;倘若這是她所願
then I will help her do that.
&lrm;那我便會助她一臂之力
Then that leaves me
&lrm;若是如此
no reason to keep Naksu alive.
&lrm;那我便沒有理由再留著落壽的命
You must stop thinking of it that way
&lrm;請妳收起這種想法
if you want your daughter, Jin Bu-yeon,
&lrm;這樣妳女兒陳復妍
to return to you safe and sound.
&lrm;才能安然無恙地回到妳身邊
What?
&lrm;什麼？
Bu-yeon will return?
&lrm;復妍會回到我身邊？
What do you mean?
&lrm;此話何意？
Naksu's soul will disappear soon,
&lrm;落壽的靈魂很快就會消失
and Jin Bu-yeon will take over the body.
&lrm;那副身軀將會徹底被陳復妍接管
That is what Master Lee told me.
&lrm;這是李先生告訴我的
He told me Bu-yeon's soul did not remain in that body.
&lrm;他分明告訴我 &lrm;復妍的靈魂已經不復存在
Then has he been deceiving me all this time?
&lrm;難道他一直在騙我？
Ask him yourself.
&lrm;這個妳親自去問李先生吧
Just let her
&lrm;即便只有片刻
stay where she wants
&lrm;也請妳讓她留在喜愛之處
with the person she wishes to be with
&lrm;與想攜手同行的人
for a while.
&lrm;待在一起吧
This is both a threat…
&lrm;這雖是威脅…
and a plea.
&lrm;卻也是請求
Why are you empty-handed?
&lrm;你為何空手而來？
Why did you not bring what I asked?
&lrm;我叫你帶的東西呢？
You also have this.
&lrm;你也有相同之物吧
I did not bring it, as it did not seem necessary.
&lrm;我覺得用不到，所以便沒帶來
I guess that means
&lrm;你說沒帶來
you really do possess it.
&lrm;就表示你真的有
The fact that you know I possess it
&lrm;既然邸下知道我有此物
means you also know how I came into this world.
&lrm;那必然也知曉我是如何出世的了
If you do not intend to fight me over the Gold Plaque,
&lrm;倘若你不想拿著金牌與我為敵
go to North Fortress, Jang Uk.
&lrm;那就去北城吧，張煜
I will hide behind Jin Mu like you said,
&lrm;我將如你所說，躲在陳武身後
and I order you to go far away.
&lrm;你便就此遠去吧
I, Jang Uk of the Jang family,
&lrm;張氏家族的張煜
will abide by the royal order and leave for North Fortress.
&lrm;願奉旨前往北城
Thank you for honoring my command.
&lrm;謝謝你願意受命
Do not waste any more time
&lrm;那麼事不宜遲
and prepare to leave in a few days.
&lrm;你好好準備，這幾日便出發吧
I planned to threaten Park Jin of Songrim to put pressure on Jang Uk.
&lrm;我本為了逼迫張煜 &lrm;還打算去要脅松林的朴進
I am surprised that you made him succumb to you
&lrm;沒想到邸下竟直接向張煜亮出金牌
by revealing the existence of the Gold Plaque.
&lrm;使他乖乖就範
I realized something as I stood against him recently.
&lrm;不久前我與他對峙，明白了一件事
Jang Uk does not fight for personal gain,
&lrm;張煜此人通常不為私利
but to protect those around him.
&lrm;只會為守護周遭之物而戰
So if I challenged him with the Gold Plaque,
&lrm;因此只要我亮出金牌，向他宣戰
I figured he would back down to protect his loved ones.
&lrm;與其爭權奪利 &lrm;他自然寧願為求全而讓步
Park Jin of Songrim also did not do anything to me
&lrm;松林的朴進當初也為了守護張煜
to protect Jang Uk.
&lrm;而奈何不了我
They are restrained by justice and fail to do what is necessary.
&lrm;這些人就是心志軟弱 &lrm;才會被無謂的情義束縛
It is a sign of weakness.
&lrm;而動彈不得
I see.
&lrm;原來如此
Gwanju.
&lrm;館主
Ever since a few days ago, I cannot seem to find my turtle.
&lrm;不久前我養在這裡的烏龜 &lrm;突然不見蹤影了
That insignificant and weak animal does not suit you, Your Royal Highness.
&lrm;那種動物弱小又不足掛齒 &lrm;不適合邸下
Do not allow yourself to cling to something so trivial.
&lrm;您就別將心思放在如此無用之處了
Did you get rid of it
&lrm;你是故意為之
to prevent me from doing so?
&lrm;好讓我整頓心思嗎？
Do you wish to find it again?
&lrm;邸下想再將牠尋回嗎？
No.
&lrm;不必了
I just think it is a shame because I was told it had good energy.
&lrm;我只是聽聞牠氣息甚好 &lrm;有些惋惜罷了
The peacock in the garden also holds good energy.
&lrm;邸下若要氣息甚好的動物 &lrm;還有園子裡的孔雀啊
They are nothing but animals that merely exist to please the eye.
&lrm;牠們都不過是供人賞玩的動物罷了
Understood.
&lrm;好吧
So have you agreed to go to North Fortress?
&lrm;所以你決定要去北城了嗎？
Yes, I have decided to go.
&lrm;是，我決定前往
It concerns me
&lrm;我真擔心
that they might be sending you away as part of a scheme.
&lrm;他們刻意將你送走，怕是圖謀不軌
The Crown Prince showed me his Gold Plaque
&lrm;世子向我亮出金牌
and asked if I was willing to fight.
&lrm;問我是否能夠挺身而戰
If I decide to engage in this fight,
&lrm;倘若我決定參與這場大戰
will you stand behind me like you did last time?
&lrm;首領，你還會像上次一樣 &lrm;站在我身後嗎？
What exactly is your target in this fight?
&lrm;這場大戰你是為了對抗什麼？
What is it that you wish to protect?
&lrm;你想守護的又是什麼？
Are you acting in careful deliberation?
&lrm;你可有確切的目的？
Yes, I know where I am targeting,
&lrm;有，我的目標明確
and I have decided to accept this fight
&lrm;並且為了必須守護的一切
in order to protect what I must.
&lrm;我已決定參與這場大戰
What brings you here?
&lrm;妳有何事？
Young Lady Heo wishes to meet you.
&lrm;我家小姐想見妳一面
At Sejukwon?
&lrm;是要我去細竹院嗎？
No.
&lrm;不是
She wishes to meet where Young Master Jang frequently visits.
&lrm;她要妳到阿煜少爺常去的地方找她
We received another message from Seoho Fortress.
&lrm;西湖城又捎來消息
Your father is very worried about you.
&lrm;你父親十分擔心你
I will write him a letter.
&lrm;我會親自傳信回去
Right.
&lrm;對了
We should have asked Lord Park to take the letter
&lrm;你先前放在行囊裡 &lrm;打算送到西湖城的信
that was inside your luggage when he visited Seoho Fortress.
&lrm;之前應該請首領一道帶去的
You saw the letter that was in my luggage?
&lrm;你看到我放在行囊裡的信了？
Yes, Young Lady Heo took it.
&lrm;是啊，贇鈺小姐拿來的
Where is Young Lady Heo?
&lrm;贇鈺小姐在哪？
Why did you ask me to meet you here?
&lrm;妳為何將我找來此處？
I heard this graveyard
&lrm;聽聞
was built by Young Master Jang after he started killing soul shifters.
&lrm;這裡是張煜少爺消滅還魂人後 &lrm;為他們堆砌而成的墳墓
Then there should also be a grave for Naksu, the one who killed him.
&lrm;因此我想此處也會有 &lrm;當年殺害他的落壽之墳
That must be it.
&lrm;原來是這一座
You said you have no recollection of who you are, right?
&lrm;妳說妳不記得自己是誰對吧？
Are you not curious?
&lrm;難道妳不好奇嗎？
Why do you care?
&lrm;這與妳何干？
Because I am curious too.
&lrm;因為我也開始好奇了
So I came to confirm something.
&lrm;所以我打算來確定一下
What is that?
&lrm;那是什麼？
I am a physician.
&lrm;我是大夫
I would never do anything to harm anyone.
&lrm;不會做出害人之舉
I am merely trying
&lrm;我只是想為我們的疑問
to satisfy our curiosity.
&lrm;找到答案
-There should be a blue mark here. -What are you doing?
&lrm;-這裡應該要有藍色印記啊 &lrm;-妳在做什麼？
-Young Master Seo. -What do you think you are doing?
&lrm;-阿律少爺 &lrm;-妳這是在做什麼？
Are you all right?
&lrm;妳沒事吧？
I am all right.
&lrm;我沒事
Why did you splash that on me?
&lrm;妳為何要將它潑在我身上？
-Because you are a soul shifter-- -Enough.
&lrm;-因為妳是還魂… &lrm;-夠了
If you are doing this because of my letter, just stop.
&lrm;若妳是看了我的信才這麼做 &lrm;那請妳到此為止
I will explain everything.
&lrm;我可以跟妳解釋
Young Lady Bu-yeon, you should hurry and wash off the medicine.
&lrm;復妍小姐，妳快去用水 &lrm;洗淨身上潑到的藥
All right.
&lrm;好
Did you read my letter?
&lrm;妳看了我的信嗎？
I did.
&lrm;對
If everything in that letter is true,
&lrm;若你信中所說全部屬實
why are you letting her be?
&lrm;為何還要放任她不管？
She is Naksu, is she not?
&lrm;她可是落壽
The blue marks
&lrm;兩道藍色的光
bloomed in her eyes like flowers.
&lrm;像花一樣綻放在她眼裡
Am I…
&lrm;難道…
her?
&lrm;那就是我？
That woman…
&lrm;那個人
hurt Young Master Jang very deeply.
&lrm;帶給阿煜少爺無法抹滅的傷痛
I could not let her stay beside him only to see him get hurt again.
&lrm;我不能放任少爺將那種人留在身邊 &lrm;再次受到傷害
So I wanted to show her who she is
&lrm;所以我要讓她知道真相
and make her leave.
&lrm;主動離開
You do not need to let her know.
&lrm;即便妳沒讓她知道真相
Her soul will soon disappear.
&lrm;她的靈魂也很快就會消失
I just wanted…
&lrm;我只是…
to let her stay like this for a bit longer.
&lrm;想讓她這樣多維持一段時日
You have poisoned me again,
&lrm;我的瘋狂師父
crazy master.
&lrm;妳這次又下毒了
It is that tree.
&lrm;就是那裡
I have been here before.
&lrm;我真的來過這裡
Do you wish to go up there?
&lrm;妳想上去嗎？
Fine.
&lrm;好
I will take you to the top of that tree.
&lrm;我就帶妳登上樹頂
I knew the moment I saw you.
&lrm;我第一眼就認出來了
My crazy master.
&lrm;我的瘋狂師父
I do not need a pupil who does not improve.
&lrm;我不需要沒有成長的徒弟
Just die if you are not going to do anything.
&lrm;要是什麼都不做，那你乾脆去死算了
Master!
&lrm;師父
You are my master.
&lrm;我的師父
Master, I finally did it.
&lrm;師父，我辦到了
They are bird's eggs.
&lrm;是鳥蛋呢
I also missed you.
&lrm;我也很想妳
I like you a lot.
&lrm;我真的很喜歡你
Just one.
&lrm;只有一枚
I will hold your hand as if it is a ring.
&lrm;只有妳，我要一輩子 &lrm;這樣把妳戴在手上
They were all my memories.
&lrm;那全都是我的記憶
I was the owner of the blue jade.
&lrm;我就是這顆藍玉的主人
I was his master,
&lrm;也是他的師父
Naksu.
&lrm;落壽
You must be Jin Bu-yeon, the owner of this body.
&lrm;妳就是這副身軀的主人陳復妍吧
I see you have finally realized
&lrm;看來妳終究還是覺醒
who you really are.
&lrm;知曉自己的身分了
What a shame.
&lrm;可惜了
If you found out after I retrieved all of my divine powers,
&lrm;倘若妳是在我神力全然復原後才覺醒
you would have been able to leave with no sadness.
&lrm;就能不必如此悲傷地離去了
Thanks to you, my body stayed whole without running wild,
&lrm;多虧有妳，我才能免於失控 &lrm;保持肉身完善
and I have regained most of my divine powers.
&lrm;神力也幾乎要復原了
You will soon have to leave this body,
&lrm;而妳並非這副身軀的主人
for it is not your own.
&lrm;很快便得離去
Someone from Sejukwon came to see her?
&lrm;細竹院派人來過？
Yes.
&lrm;對
Does that mean she went to Sejukwon?
&lrm;所以她去細竹院了嗎？
No, I offered to take her there if that was where she was headed.
&lrm;沒有，我當時跟小姐說 &lrm;若要去細竹院，我可以陪她去
But she said she was going somewhere else.
&lrm;但她說要去別的地方
All right, you can go.
&lrm;好，我知道了
Where did she go? She said she would wait.
&lrm;不是說要等我嗎？她跑去哪了？
It is not here.
&lrm;不在這了
That jade makes things even more confusing.
&lrm;我的記憶好像都要被它搞混了
Seeing that tree for myself will help me find out who I really am.
&lrm;感覺見到那棵樹 &lrm;就能知道我究竟是誰了
I wonder if she actually went there.
&lrm;難道她真的去那裡了？
She said she did not wish to go.
&lrm;她不是說不去了嗎？
This is where they first met each other.
&lrm;這裡是他們初次相遇的地方
He proposed to her here as well.
&lrm;也是他求婚的地方
Young Master Seo.
&lrm;少爺
Is something the matter with Young Lady Bu-yeon?
&lrm;復妍小姐發生什麼事了嗎？
Send someone to Uk's place and tell them that she is here.
&lrm;麻煩妳派人到阿煜家 &lrm;通知他們復妍小姐在這吧
Here you are.
&lrm;原來妳在這裡
I waited but you did not come.
&lrm;我一直等不到妳
I almost went to Danhyanggok to look for you.
&lrm;還以為妳自己跑去斷響谷 &lrm;差點要去找妳了
I went there.
&lrm;我去過了
And now…
&lrm;所以…
I found out who I am.
&lrm;也知道我是誰了
Does that mean you regained your memory?
&lrm;也就是說妳恢復記憶了對吧？
Yes.
&lrm;對
Then why did you come here instead of coming home?
&lrm;那妳怎麼窩在這裡不回家？
I came looking for you because you did not come.
&lrm;我等不到妳，只好出來找妳了
I am sorry. I know I said I would wait.
&lrm;對不起，我說好要等你的
But…
&lrm;可是
I can no longer wait for you.
&lrm;我以後不能再等你了
I remembered something very important.
&lrm;因為我想起了非常重要的記憶
Let me make myself clear.
&lrm;我先說好
I do not know what kind of person you remember yourself to be.
&lrm;不管在那些失而復得的記憶中 &lrm;妳是什麼樣的人
But I do not care.
&lrm;我都不在乎
Whatever those memories are,
&lrm;無論妳有什麼記憶
-they do not matter to me. -They matter to me.
&lrm;我都不介意
Among the many things I remember…
&lrm;因為在我失而復得的記憶裡…
there was a man I deeply cared for.
&lrm;有一個我深愛的人
You really have a way
&lrm;妳還真是
of surprising me when it is least expected.
&lrm;時不時就語出驚人，讓我措手不及
-What is your point? -But you see…
&lrm;-然後呢？ &lrm;-然後…
he does not recognize me, even if I am in front of him.
&lrm;即便我就在他面前，他也認不出我
Is that so?
&lrm;是嗎？
Then why not tell him that it is you?
&lrm;那妳何不告訴他，讓他認出妳？
I cannot.
&lrm;我不能這麼做
I hurt him too gravely.
&lrm;因為我已經傷他太深了
I cannot tell him it is me…
&lrm;我既不能告訴他…
or go near him.
&lrm;也不能靠近他
I feel too guilty to stay with you.
&lrm;我太愧疚了，沒臉待在你身邊
I shall go to Jinyowon.
&lrm;我還是回辰曜院吧
No, wait.
&lrm;等一下
You are just going to leave?
&lrm;妳就這樣走了嗎？
You left after you said you would wait,
&lrm;妳說要等我，結果跑出門
and now you are leaving me because you remember someone else?
&lrm;現在突然想起另一個人就要走？
Then am I supposed to act fine
&lrm;那我就應該欣然接受
and wish you good luck with him?
&lrm;祝福你們兩個嗎？
No, wait.
&lrm;不是啊
You said you cannot be with him and he does not recognize you.
&lrm;妳不是說他認不出妳 &lrm;妳也不能靠近他嗎？
I really…
&lrm;我以前…
liked him a lot.
&lrm;真的很喜歡他
I liked him more than he liked me.
&lrm;其實我愛他更甚於他愛我
But I never had a chance to tell him.
&lrm;但我卻從來沒有好好告訴過他
Jang Uk.
&lrm;張煜
Turn the light back on.
&lrm;你把燈點燃吧
Keep your head straight.
&lrm;讓自己清醒一點
Keep your promise and let me go.
&lrm;按照約定放手讓我走就行了
I am sorry.
&lrm;對不起
Mother.
&lrm;娘
Bu-yeon came home.
&lrm;姐姐回來了
Bu-yeon?
&lrm;復妍嗎？
Mother.
&lrm;娘
I have returned home
&lrm;我按照約定
as promised.
&lrm;回來了
Young Lady Bu-yeon went back to Jinyowon?
&lrm;小姐回辰曜院了？
Why? She said she was going to stay.
&lrm;她明明說要留在這啊 &lrm;怎麼突然走了？
I heard Lady Jin is not doing so well.
&lrm;聽聞陳院長身子十分不適
Did she leave because she was worried?
&lrm;她是因為擔心，所以先回去了嗎？
She wants to stay there for now.
&lrm;總之她會先待在辰曜院
Do not worry.
&lrm;妳別擔心
I see.
&lrm;嗯
I wonder if Lady Jin is in a severe condition.
&lrm;陳院長狀況很差嗎？
We prepared your room for you.
&lrm;姐姐，妳的房間都整理好了
Why do you wish to stay here?
&lrm;妳怎麼還是想住這？
This place is more familiar to me.
&lrm;這裡我住慣了，比較自在
Besides, I do not wish to see anyone.
&lrm;何況我也不想遇到任何人
I heard you will be heading to North Fortress.
&lrm;聽說你要去北城了
Yes.
&lrm;嗯
I have discussed it with the leader, so do not be concerned.
&lrm;這件事我已告知首領 &lrm;也跟他討論過，妳別擔心
All right.
&lrm;好
Did you tell Young Lady Bu-yeon?
&lrm;那你也跟復妍小姐說了嗎？
No.
&lrm;我來不及說
I should have told her,
&lrm;本來應該告訴她的
but I did not get a chance to.
&lrm;但是沒機會開口
I knew the moment I saw you.
&lrm;我第一眼就認出來了
You are my master.
&lrm;我的師父
You are my husband.
&lrm;我的夫婿
Jang Uk of the Jang family
&lrm;本王在此下令
will be appointed as the general of North Fortress.
&lrm;封張氏家族張煜為北城大將軍
Seo Gyeong, who possessed the power of Hwansu,
&lrm;過去練就換水之力的徐經
moved to Seoho Fortress to prevent himself from becoming a threat to the royal family
&lrm;為不造成王室威脅 &lrm;便退居西方邊疆的西湖城
and thus achieved unity.
&lrm;以致天下太平
Jang Uk's transfer to North Fortress
&lrm;張煜退居北城
will bring the same kind of peace and stability to Daeho Fortress.
&lrm;必能維持大湖城的平和與安定
I shall protect Daeho Fortress with the help of Cheonbugwan.
&lrm;大湖城有我和天府館來鎮守
We will soon begin to prepare for the lake's rite to pray for rain.
&lrm;再過不久我們便要 &lrm;準備舉行祈雨的敬天大祭
Jang Uk, you shall travel north and wait for the black clouds
&lrm;張煜，你就在北方等待為世間帶來
that will bring energy to the world.
&lrm;充沛水氣的烏雲吧
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
&lrm;是
I hear you are married.
&lrm;聽聞你已成親
Will your wife be joining you?
&lrm;妻子是否一同前往？
The place is far and rough, so she will not be coming with me.
&lrm;北城艱險遙遠，她不會與我同去
She will be lonely here without you.
&lrm;新婚妻子獨留於此，定會十分孤單
You have a long road ahead of you. Travel safely.
&lrm;無論如何，路途遙遠，你務必保重
Yes, Your Majesty.
&lrm;好的
Naksu's soul will disappear soon,
&lrm;落壽的靈魂很快就會消失
and Jin Bu-yeon will take over the body.
&lrm;那副身軀將會徹底被陳復妍接管
That is what Master Lee told me.
&lrm;這是李先生告訴我的
Did Naksu's soul disappear
&lrm;難道真如他所說
just like he said it would?
&lrm;落壽的靈魂會消失？
No.
&lrm;不
He said Bu-yeon would return if that happened.
&lrm;他說的是這樣復妍才會回到我身邊
But that is not yet my daughter, Bu-yeon.
&lrm;所以現在這個還不是我女兒復妍
If he leaves for North Fortress…
&lrm;他要是去了北城…
I will never get to see him again.
&lrm;我就再也見不到他了吧
Shall I try calling for her?
&lrm;要呼喚她嗎？
But what if she does not come?
&lrm;那萬一她不來呢？
There was a man I deeply cared for.
&lrm;有一個我深愛的人
Who could it be?
&lrm;到底是誰？
Who could he be?
&lrm;是哪個傢伙？
Three years have passed since she lost her memory.
&lrm;既然是她遺失的記憶 &lrm;那少說也是三年前的事
How could she still have such strong feelings for him?
&lrm;都過了三年，感情還這麼深刻？
I liked him more than he liked me.
&lrm;其實我愛他更甚於他愛我
I guess it is possible
&lrm;好吧
if she liked him a lot more.
&lrm;如果她比較愛他，那也不無可能
But still, how could she dump me in less than a day?
&lrm;但她也不能半天之內就把我拋下吧？
Am I more insignificant than a brazier on a summer day?
&lrm;難道我比盛夏的爐火還不如嗎？
She has a cold heart.
&lrm;真無情
Turn the light back on.
&lrm;你把燈點燃吧
You totally deceived me.
&lrm;妳這是欺騙我的感情
You should have
&lrm;既然要離開我
remembered everything before I fell for you.
&lrm;妳就應該在我失去理智前恢復記憶啊
How am I supposed to turn the light back on now?
&lrm;事到如今我要怎麼把燈點燃？
I miss her like crazy
&lrm;聽她說完那些話
even after what she said.
&lrm;我還是想她想得要命
I have informed Young Lady Bu-yeon of your arrival.
&lrm;我已經轉告復妍小姐你來了
Bu-yeon is aware
&lrm;我姐姐已經知道
that you are leaving for North Fortress tomorrow.
&lrm;你明日要出發去北城了
She wishes you a safe trip.
&lrm;她要我轉告你路上小心
Tell her that I will visit
&lrm;麻煩妳轉告她
once I return.
&lrm;等我回來會再來找她
What is going on?
&lrm;怎麼回事？
Jang Uk is clinging to her.
&lrm;張煜不願放手
Does that mean Bu-yeon is rejecting him?
&lrm;是姐姐要離開他？
You asked me to visit secretly
&lrm;是妳叫我翻牆
by climbing over the wall.
&lrm;悄悄潛入的
I took your advice to heart.
&lrm;我接受了妳的建議
I should have destroyed this place the last time I came.
&lrm;我上次來的時候 &lrm;就應該把這裡夷為平地
Why are you back in this room?
&lrm;妳為什麼又住進這裡？
Because I prefer it here.
&lrm;我住這裡比較自在
It gives me space to think.
&lrm;方便我一個人靜靜
I thought you were leaving.
&lrm;我以為你走了
Why did you come back?
&lrm;怎麼又回來了？
You stood there watching me leave,
&lrm;因為妳只看著我的背影
so I came to say goodbye.
&lrm;我只好進來當面道別
I heard you are traveling far away.
&lrm;聽說你要去很遠的地方
Goodbye.
&lrm;一路小心
"Goodbye"?
&lrm;一路小心？
I usually have no problem leaving people.
&lrm;我本來面對離別 &lrm;都是說聲保重，轉身就走
But I was so dumbfounded that I had to ask.
&lrm;但我實在無法接受 &lrm;所以還是得來找妳問清楚
I get it.
&lrm;我懂
He may feel more dear to you now that you got your memory back.
&lrm;妳突然想起那個人 &lrm;確實可能更加愧疚或刻骨銘心
But then,
&lrm;但是
why did you fall for me at first sight?
&lrm;妳又為什麼第一眼就認定是我？
I want to ask if I look similar to him,
&lrm;我實在很想問妳 &lrm;難道是因為我與他相像
but that also feels inappropriate to ask.
&lrm;但這麼問似乎又太過失禮
Do not ask.
&lrm;別問了
I cannot tell you anything.
&lrm;我沒辦法給你任何答案
Do we really look alike?
&lrm;我們真的很像嗎？
Did you fall for me
&lrm;真的是因為我們長得像
because I looked just like him?
&lrm;妳才第一眼就認定是我嗎？
Let us say that happened.
&lrm;就當作是這樣吧
I liked you because you looked like him,
&lrm;就當我是因為你像他才喜歡你
and you liked me because you were confused.
&lrm;而你是因為把我當成她才喜歡我
Let us leave it at that.
&lrm;以此作結吧
I cannot do that!
&lrm;就說了我做不到！
I thought about it over and over again.
&lrm;我已經想了一遍又一遍
The reason I wanted you to stay was not that I was confused or crazy.
&lrm;我之所以留妳，根本不是因為 &lrm;失去理智或哪根筋不對
I just…
&lrm;我就是…
I just like you that much.
&lrm;喜歡妳到了失去理智的地步
I had buried my memories,
&lrm;是妳把我停下腳步
but you took them out and helped me face them.
&lrm;埋進墳墓的回憶重新挖掘出來的
You held my hand when I never thought I could.
&lrm;當我以為再也無法握住誰 &lrm;是妳牽起我的手
You helped me sleep when I could not.
&lrm;當我夜不成眠，是妳讓我安穩入睡
And for that…
&lrm;所以…
I cannot stop anymore.
&lrm;我已經無法克制自己的心了
So I will be the brazier on a summer day.
&lrm;我決定當一回無足輕重的盛夏爐火
This time, I will be the one waiting…
&lrm;這次換我等妳
until you begin to miss me.
&lrm;直到妳覺得不捨為止
I will go now.
&lrm;我走了
I will return sooner than expected.
&lrm;我會比預期更快回來
Stay well.
&lrm;妳好好照顧自己
Are you leaving now?
&lrm;你這就要出發了嗎？
Yes.
&lrm;對
The last mage of Jeongjingak is leaving.
&lrm;連精進閣最後一名術士都要離開
That place is going to be completely empty now.
&lrm;這下精進閣真的是空無一人了
This does not feel right.
&lrm;我還是覺得不行
I shall go to North Fortress with you.
&lrm;我也跟你一起去北城吧
I cannot let you go there alone.
&lrm;我不能讓你一個人去啊
Then what about me?
&lrm;那我怎麼辦呢？
Aunt, you should stay beside my uncle.
&lrm;叔母，妳應該留在我叔父身邊才對啊
Did you meet Young Lady Bu-yeon?
&lrm;你跟小姐見過面了吧？
Did she not offer to go with you?
&lrm;她沒說要跟你去嗎？
I thought she would insist on going.
&lrm;我還以為她一定會堅持要陪你去
She had her reasons.
&lrm;礙於某些原因，她沒辦法跟我走
Is Master Lee not here? I wanted to see him before I left.
&lrm;李先生不在嗎？ &lrm;我本想在離開前見他一面
He stayed at Sejukwon for a few days to treat Yul,
&lrm;他最近為了醫治阿律 &lrm;在細竹院待了幾天
but he must have left again, seeing he is no longer there.
&lrm;但目前不在，不曉得又跑去哪了
I see.
&lrm;是嗎？
Should we not tell Uk about Naksu?
&lrm;我們是不是應該 &lrm;把落壽的事告訴阿煜？
I wanted to tell him, but Lady Jin was against it.
&lrm;起初我也想告訴他，但是陳院長反對
Now that Naksu's soul is going to disappear,
&lrm;但現在與其告訴他 &lrm;落壽的靈魂即將消失
it makes me think that he may be better off not knowing.
&lrm;我想還是讓他被蒙在鼓裡好一點
If he finds out…
&lrm;他若是知道了
it will be agonizing for both of them.
&lrm;他們倆都會陷入痛苦吧
Jang Uk will agonize over something bigger than the pain of losing a loved one.
&lrm;對張煜而言，除了失去摯愛 &lrm;他還要承受更大的痛苦
He possesses the power of Hwansu.
&lrm;他擁有換水之力
If he wants, he can get rid of Jin Bu-yeon's soul from that body
&lrm;只要他願意
and keep Naksu's soul.
&lrm;留下落壽的靈魂
That is forbidden sorcery, just like the alchemy of souls.
&lrm;這應該是類似還魂術的禁術吧
That is why it will be agonizing.
&lrm;所以才說是痛苦啊
He will not be able to save her even though he has the power to.
&lrm;他有能力救她，卻不得為之
Jang Uk will agonize over having to make a choice
&lrm;若是一般人 &lrm;根本無須面臨這般痛苦的抉擇
that no ordinary human would ever have to make.
&lrm;而張煜卻勢必要承受
It looks like Uk and Jin Bu-yeon are having problems.
&lrm;阿煜跟陳復妍之間不知道怎麼了
According to Young Lady Jin,
&lrm;我聽超妍小姐說
Uk went to see her sister, but she refused to meet him.
&lrm;阿煜去找陳復妍 &lrm;但她根本不肯見阿煜
Do you think Uk did not tell her about going to North Fortress?
&lrm;難道阿煜沒告訴她要去北城的事嗎？
You are a sacred animal with a rare kind of energy.
&lrm;你真是具備珍稀之氣的神獸
A turtle that possesses the energy of the Black Tortoise.
&lrm;是隻帶有玄武之氣的神龜
They say the Black Tortoise guides those who are lost
&lrm;玄武會為迷途徬徨之人
and leads them in the right direction.
&lrm;指引明智且正確的方向
I see you are heading over to help someone find their way.
&lrm;看來你正在奮力走向某人
Will Cheonbugwan be starting to make preparations for the lake's rite?
&lrm;天府館是否要正式開始 &lrm;準備敬天大祭了？
Will your secret organization be getting involved as well?
&lrm;你會動用你的密團嗎？
I will soon introduce you to the secret organization.
&lrm;很快我也會讓邸下參與密團的集會
You promised to make me as powerful as Jang Uk.
&lrm;你說過會讓我擁有等同張煜的力量
Tell me if you need my help in achieving that goal.
&lrm;倘若需要我的幫助就儘管說
I shall wholly support you.
&lrm;我會竭盡全力幫你
-What is that? -What happened?
&lrm;-那是什麼？ &lrm;-怎麼回事啊？
-Goodness. -They look like birds.
&lrm;-天啊 &lrm;-看起來像鳥
-What in the world are they? -What are those things?
&lrm;-這究竟是何物？ &lrm;-這是什麼啊？
Are they birds?
&lrm;這是鳥吧
What are they doing in Lake Gyeongcheondaeho?
&lrm;這種東西為何會漂浮在敬天大湖上？
Hundreds of the same kind of earthenware were found all over the lake.
&lrm;突然有數百個同樣的陶器 &lrm;漂到湖岸各處
They must have drifted to shore
&lrm;看來他們本想暗中運入
after being discarded during an attempt to smuggle them in.
&lrm;怕被逮到便丟進湖中 &lrm;於是都漂到岸邊了
They are just bird-shaped earthenware,
&lrm;雖說只是鳥形的陶器
but they give off an ominous feeling.
&lrm;但光看就覺得不吉利
Now that people have seen them in Lake Gyeongcheondaeho,
&lrm;敬天大湖出現這種東西
it will cause an uproar.
&lrm;這下要傳聞四起了
No matter how bad the drought gets, it will not dry up Lake Gyeongcheondaeho.
&lrm;乾旱再嚴重，敬天大湖也不可能枯竭
What are you talking about?
&lrm;怎麼不可能？
Lake Gyeongcheondaeho once dried up
&lrm;200年前發生大旱時
during the burning drought that occurred 200 years ago.
&lrm;敬天大湖不就完全乾涸了嗎？
-I am telling you. -Goodness, you are right.
&lrm;-所以不無可能 &lrm;-對喔，這下糟了，這到底…
-Be careful! -What are you doing?
&lrm;-你小心點 &lrm;-你別亂碰啊
-Why would you touch that? -Goodness.
&lrm;-你又不知道那是什麼 &lrm;-唉唷
-My goodness. -What is that?
&lrm;-天啊 &lrm;-這到底是什麼？
The capital is in an uproar thanks to the earthenware
&lrm;我丟棄在湖中的陶器漂到了岸邊
that I discarded into the lake.
&lrm;導致京城百姓議論紛紛
Everyone is worried that Lake Gyeongcheondaeho will dry up.
&lrm;人人都在擔心敬天大湖要乾涸了
That is good to hear.
&lrm;這樣正好
Dissent among the people will cause the Unanimous Assembly
&lrm;百姓惶惶不安 &lrm;萬長會必定會全力以赴
to actively take part in the rite for the lake.
&lrm;籌辦敬天大祭
Songrim will strengthen their guard.
&lrm;但松林恐怕會更加戒備
It will become more difficult to bring in the earthenware from the volcano.
&lrm;如此一來，要從火山將陶器運來 &lrm;就難上加難了
They will be used for the rite?
&lrm;這是祭典要用的東西？
Bring them in with the gifts for the King that get imported from the volcano.
&lrm;那就跟火山來的貢品一起運進來吧
Then Songrim will not be able to do anything about it.
&lrm;這麼一來，松林也奈何不了我們了
We need to place them throughout the canals before the rite.
&lrm;我們必須在敬天大祭前 &lrm;將它們置於水路各處
Will you allow me to do that, Your Royal Highness?
&lrm;不知邸下可否幫忙？
I will inform the men of the Night Watch who guard the city at night.
&lrm;我再知會夜間負責守備京城的守夜廳
You may use them.
&lrm;他們就供你差遣
With their help, it will be an easy task.
&lrm;有了守夜廳的幫助，想必能事半功倍
Will these also be used to dry up the world?
&lrm;這也是用來讓大地乾涸的嗎？
They just exist to help the one that is real.
&lrm;這些只是為了輔助真正的火鳥罷了
And that is
&lrm;真正的火鳥
the fire bird that lives inside Jinyowon.
&lrm;是辰曜院裡那一隻
If we want that, we must gain control
&lrm;若要得到牠，我們就必須操縱萬長會
of Jinyowon with the help of the Unanimous assembly.
&lrm;藉此得到辰曜院
I asked you to come to discuss something
&lrm;明天將召開萬長會
before attending tomorrow's Unanimous Assembly.
&lrm;我請妳過來是要先商量一些事
You wished to discuss something with me?
&lrm;你要跟我商量事情？
The priestess who will be dancing for the rite
&lrm;我打算從其他家族中挑選出
will be picked from another family.
&lrm;在祭典上跳敬天舞的神女
What?
&lrm;什麼？
The dance for the lake's rite
&lrm;敬天大祭的敬天舞
has been the job of a Jinyowon priestess for centuries.
&lrm;向來都是由辰曜院神女負責
Why would you pick a priestess from another family?
&lrm;怎能突然從其他家族挑選？
There is no one in Jinyowon who possesses the divine powers
&lrm;眼下辰曜院根本 &lrm;沒有具備足夠神力的神女
to dance for the lake's rite.
&lrm;可以負責敬天舞
I am capable, and so are my two daughters.
&lrm;還有我這個院長和兩個女兒
Ho-gyeong.
&lrm;姐
I am merely here to give you notice.
&lrm;我找妳來不過是先知會妳一聲
The mages of the Unanimous Assembly have already made up their minds.
&lrm;此事萬長會術士都已拿定主意
If you continue to feed your ego like this,
&lrm;妳再這麼要面子
you will only end up embarrassing yourself.
&lrm;小心最後更難堪
You will be the one embarrassing yourself.
&lrm;到時候難堪的是你
Jinyowon will not provide you
&lrm;你所籌備的敬天大祭上
with any of its artifacts to help you hold the lake's rite.
&lrm;將用到的所有法器
The royal family and Unanimous Assembly stand on my side.
&lrm;萬長會跟王室都支持我
You will eventually have to give in.
&lrm;妳確定能夠堅持不借？
Did you forget that Jinyowon owns a plaque
&lrm;你難道忘了辰曜院有一面
that gives us the power to reject the King's orders?
&lrm;連王命都能拒絕的傍牌？
Bu-yeon.
&lrm;姐姐
Is it not suffocating here?
&lrm;妳待在這不悶嗎？
I am going to meet Young Master Park.
&lrm;我要去找當具少爺
You should also get some air.
&lrm;妳也出去走走吧
Mother is not home right now.
&lrm;娘現在不在
I am fine.
&lrm;不用了
My lady.
&lrm;超妍小姐
Lady Jin asked you to urgently come to Cheonbugwan
&lrm;院長請妳盡快帶著辰曜院的傍牌
with the Jinyowon Plaque.
&lrm;前去天府館
Now?
&lrm;現在？
Right this moment?
&lrm;立刻嗎？
She had a dispute with Jin Mu, the Gwanju of Cheonbugwan.
&lrm;院長和天府館的陳武館主起了爭執
You should hurry over.
&lrm;妳還是快去吧
-Did you say Jin Mu of Cheonbugwan? -Yes.
&lrm;-妳剛才說天府館的陳武嗎？ &lrm;-對
Then I will go instead.
&lrm;那我去吧
You?
&lrm;妳要去？
I am the eldest daughter.
&lrm;我是陳家長女
The Jinyowon Plaque is a very valuable item.
&lrm;可是辰曜院的傍牌非常貴重
If I let you take it,
&lrm;讓妳送去的話
I could get scolded by Mother.
&lrm;我說不定會被娘狠狠教訓一頓
Are you going to be the heir of Jinyowon?
&lrm;妳要成為辰曜院繼承人嗎？
Then you will have to marry a man who is willing to move in.
&lrm;那妳丈夫就必須入贅
But you cannot marry Park Dang-gu since he is the leader of Songrim.
&lrm;朴當具已是松林首領 &lrm;妳恐怕再難與他成親
I will go.
&lrm;讓我去吧
All right.
&lrm;好
You can go instead, Bu-yeon.
&lrm;姐姐，那就妳去吧
Among the many things I remember,
&lrm;在我恢復的記憶裡
Jin Mu is one of them.
&lrm;也包括了陳武
The man who trained me to be an assassin,
&lrm;是他將我訓練成殺手
used me, and killed me.
&lrm;利用我，再殺了我
And now,
&lrm;現在
I will be meeting him.
&lrm;我就要去見他
The Jinyowon Plaque will arrive soon.
&lrm;辰曜院的傍牌很快便會送來
Your trusted plaque of Jinyowon
&lrm;妳所倚仗的辰曜院傍牌
will also be taken away tomorrow by the Unanimous Assembly.
&lrm;明天也將被萬長會收回
For what good reason?
&lrm;憑什麼收回？
You put Jinyowon in grave danger for personal reasons.
&lrm;妳因為個人緣由 &lrm;令辰曜院陷入極大的危機
He says it is not something that can be overlooked.
&lrm;他說此事不能坐視不管
-Who in the world-- -I said that.
&lrm;-究竟是誰… &lrm;-是我下的令
You made a personal promise with Songrim and allowed them
&lrm;陳湖警院長私下與松林達成協議
to disturb the fire bird's barrier inside Jinyowon.
&lrm;允許他們觸碰辰曜院內火鳥的結界
I was there when it happened.
&lrm;我在場看得一清二楚
But you helped in that matter, Your Royal Highness.
&lrm;世子，您不也是他們的幫手嗎？
The truth is that you allowed them to meddle with the barrier.
&lrm;但妳讓他們觸碰危險的結界是事實
And a spell was used inside Jinyowon,
&lrm;況且在辰曜院中使用法術
which could have woken the relics and artifacts there.
&lrm;也可能喚醒裡頭的妖器與法器
That is why
&lrm;所以
I stood outside Jinyowon to prevent that from happening.
&lrm;我當時也在辰曜院門外守著
I used my divine powers to keep everything safe.
&lrm;我已用我的神力確保一切安然無恙
Ho-gyeong.
&lrm;姐
Your hair has started to turn gray.
&lrm;妳的鬢髮都灰白了
Your divine powers have weakened and are no longer like they were before.
&lrm;妳的神力早已大不如前
That is the main reason why we are withdrawing the plaque.
&lrm;這也是我們決議收回傍牌的主因
What are you doing here?
&lrm;你怎麼會在這裡？
Did you get kicked out?
&lrm;你被趕出來了嗎？
Now that the plaque is on its way, you can just leave it here.
&lrm;既然妳們今天要將傍牌送來 &lrm;那就不必帶走了
As your brother, I do not wish
&lrm;弟弟可不想看到妳在萬長會上
to see you embarrass yourself in front of the Unanimous Assembly
&lrm;為了守住一塊傍牌 &lrm;展露自己大不如前的神力
by trying to prove your strength when we all know that you have weakened.
&lrm;最後卻落得難堪不已的下場
People from Jinyowon are here.
&lrm;辰曜院的人到了
Bu-yeon, why are you…
&lrm;復妍，妳怎麼…
Hello, I am Jin Bu-yeon, the eldest daughter of the Jin family.
&lrm;陳家長女陳復妍，拜會各位
I see you came instead of your sister, Jin Cho-yeon.
&lrm;沒想到來的不是陳超妍，而是陳復妍
Mother, here is the plaque you asked for.
&lrm;娘，我將妳交代的傍牌送來了
Thank you for bringing it here.
&lrm;辛苦妳跑一趟送過來
Now leave the plaque and go home.
&lrm;那麼妳們放下傍牌便可以回去了
Why should we leave it here?
&lrm;為何要放在這裡？
It is the Jin family's most valuable item.
&lrm;這可是陳家最為貴重的東西
Your mother has acknowledged the fact that no one in your family
&lrm;妳母親已經承認陳家沒有任何人
is capable of protecting the plaque.
&lrm;能守護這塊傍牌了
Ho-gyeong.
&lrm;姐
Put down the plaque.
&lrm;放下傍牌吧
My duty as the leader of Jinyowon
&lrm;我身為辰曜院的院長
is to protect this with my life.
&lrm;就算豁出性命也會守住這塊傍牌
What can I do to make you change your mind?
&lrm;你要我怎麼做才行？
I do not recall standing like that
&lrm;先前我求妳救我一命時
the last time I went to you to beg for my life.
&lrm;可沒有站得這麼挺
What if I prove it to you?
&lrm;可否讓我來證明？
I, the heir of Jinyowon,
&lrm;由我這個繼承人來證明
will prove that I am capable of keeping it safe.
&lrm;我有能力守護它就行了吧
I heard you lost your memory due to a severe illness.
&lrm;聽聞妳因為生過一場大病而失去記憶
They say you once possessed divine powers
&lrm;而妳被譽為陳雪蘭再世
as great as Jin Seol-ran's,
&lrm;那足以媲美她的高強神力
but you lost them with your memories.
&lrm;不也一同消失了嗎？
Both my divine powers and memories have started to come back.
&lrm;我的神力與記憶都正在恢復
Is that so?
&lrm;是嗎？
Then allow me to test your divine powers.
&lrm;那就讓我來考驗一下
Fine.
&lrm;可以
What do you wish for me to show you?
&lrm;你想如何考驗？
This prison in Cheonbugwan holds those who once performed sorcery.
&lrm;這是天府館用來 &lrm;關押使用邪術之人的監牢
Behind that door is a prison named Gwido.
&lrm;進入此門便會通往名為鬼島的監牢
The door that leads to Gwido
&lrm;這扇進入鬼島的門
was created by Jin Seol-ran, the first leader of Jinyowon,
&lrm;是由辰曜院首任院長陳雪蘭所設
so you must know it well, Ho-gyeong.
&lrm;姐，相信妳也十分清楚
Once you enter,
&lrm;一旦進去了
you can never escape this prison, even as a ghost.
&lrm;就算化成鬼也逃不出來
What do you think you are doing?
&lrm;你究竟想做什麼？
Is that where you are going to send Bu-yeon?
&lrm;你難道要將復妍關進鬼島？
I am not going to lock her up.
&lrm;我並非要將她監禁於鬼島
A long time ago, Bu-yeon managed to find
&lrm;多年以前
the ice stone that was sealed inside Lake Gyeongcheondaeho.
&lrm;復妍就連封印在 &lrm;敬天大湖的冰石都能取出
I will throw the plaque inside Gwido.
&lrm;我要將辰曜院的傍牌扔進鬼島
If she successfully brings it back in a day…
&lrm;倘若復妍能在一天內找回…
then I shall acknowledge your divine powers
&lrm;我便認同妳的神力
and cancel tomorrow's Unanimous Assembly.
&lrm;取消明天的萬長會
I will go in.
&lrm;我願意進去
No.
&lrm;不可
The wraiths of those who performed sorcery live inside Gwido.
&lrm;鬼島上還殘存許多邪術士的鬼魂
Those wraiths could kill you.
&lrm;那些鬼魂很有可能取走妳的性命
Then do you plan to surrender Jinyowon?
&lrm;那麼妳想將辰曜院拱手讓人嗎？
Have faith in your daughter's divine powers.
&lrm;相信妳女兒的神力
I promise
&lrm;我必會找到傍牌
that I will bring it back.
&lrm;平安歸來
Making her go inside Gwido is too dangerous.
&lrm;讓她進入鬼島太冒險了
A mage from the Choi family also died there 200 years ago.
&lrm;聽聞200年前崔家術士也是死於鬼島
What will you do if a Jinyowon priestess also dies in there?
&lrm;萬一辰曜院的神女在鬼島喪命
That kind of thought is also a sign of weakness.
&lrm;這也是種軟弱的心志
Find the plaque before the sun goes down.
&lrm;進去後務必在日落之前將傍牌尋回
What is that?
&lrm;話說回來，那是什麼？
I found it on my way here.
&lrm;我在路上撿到牠
The animal possesses good energy, so I would like to take it with me.
&lrm;這隻烏龜的氣息甚好 &lrm;我想帶牠一同前往
Go ahead.
&lrm;也行
I thought it was a prison.
&lrm;他分明說是監牢
I had no idea it would be this vast.
&lrm;沒想到竟如此廣闊
How am I going to find that small plaque here?
&lrm;我該如何在這裡 &lrm;找到那麼小一塊傍牌？
What if it fell into the sea?
&lrm;萬一它掉進海裡了呢？
Are you all right?
&lrm;妳沒事吧？
Jang Uk?
&lrm;張煜？
What are you doing here alone?
&lrm;妳怎麼會一個人來這種…
How are you here?
&lrm;你怎麼會在這裡？
More importantly…
&lrm;先不說這個
what is that?
&lrm;妳那是怎麼一回事？
What?
&lrm;什麼？
Those marks in your eyes.
&lrm;妳眼裡的東西
You…
&lrm;妳…
Who are you?
&lrm;究竟是誰？
ALCHEMY OF SOULS PART 2
&lrm;還魂 &lrm;第二部
Keep it in mind. Only I am allowed to come this close.
&lrm;記住了，能離妳這麼近的人只有我
Did you perhaps hear the sound of bells during that time?
&lrm;您當時是否有聽見鈴聲？
We will live in a world where the strong gain greater power
&lrm;強者將掌握更強的力量
and continue to rule forever!
&lrm;未來的天下將生生不息
All of them will have to be eradicated for this to end.
&lrm;若要終結這一切就必須斬草除根
I will likely meet my end in this place as well.
&lrm;或許我也會消失在這裡
The world they wish to see will never come.
&lrm;他們所盼望的天下絕對不可能到來
Is this not the kind of world you wanted?
&lrm;這不就是你殷殷企盼的天下嗎？
Take a close look at what it is like
&lrm;你就睜大雙眼看清楚
for someone with strength to gain and wield even greater power.
&lrm;強者掌握更強的力量恣意操縱
Subtitle translation by: Joy Lee
&lrm;字幕翻譯：吳盈臻